Alessandro Simoni

PhD Student @ Department of Engineering "Enzo Ferrari"

Modena, Italy

C +39 334 8040595 | ■ alle.simoni.as@gmail.com | 😭 alexj94.github.io | 🛅 LinkedIn | 🞓 Google Scholar

Summary _

I'm a PhD student under the tutorship of Prof. Roberto Vezzani at the International Doctorate School in ICT (Unimore, Italy) with the following research topic: "Computer Vision and Artificial Intelligence for Collaborative Robotic Environments".

My main interests are in Human-centric AI and Robotics exploiting deep learning and computer vision techniques applied to the 3D world. My research skills are related to 3D pose estimation of articulated objects and 3D object reconstruction through neural rendering techniques. I am also collaborating on a project related to the 3D reconstruction of vehicles through NeRF approaches.

Knowledge and computer skills _____

Programming languages Python (proficiency), C++, JavaScript **Libraries and Tools** PyTorch, NumPy, OpenCV, PyCharm

Domains Deep Learning, 2D/3D Computer Vision, 3D Human/Robot Pose Estimation, 3D Reconstruction

Spoken languages Italian mothertongue, English C1 (certifed ESOL Cambridge)

Working experiences _____

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant July 2023 - (July 2024)

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "Al platform with digital twins of interacting robots and people"

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant June 2022 - June 2023

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "Study of recent combinations of CNN and Vision Transformer architectures"

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant May 2020 - May 2022

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "PREVUE - Prediction of Activities and Events by Vision in an Urban Environment"

Modena, Italy

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

July 2019 - Feb. 2020

Supervisor: Prof. Rita Cucchiara

"Future urban scene generation: a deep learning approach for a 3D temporal vehicle reconstruction starting from monocular images"

Education _____

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Student internship for master's degree thesis

Modena, Italy

PhD student - Curriculum "Computer engineering and science"

Nov. 2020 - (Mar. 2024)

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Master's degree in computer engineering

Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2020

• GPA: 27.806/30. Final grade: 108/110

Modena, Italy

Bachelor's degree in computer engineering

Sep. 2013 - Feb. 2017

• GPA: 23.607/30. Final grade: 91/110

Certifications ____

First Certificate in English (FCE)

Grade A (Score 180, C1), University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations

Dec. 2020

Italian State certification exam for Engineer Profession

Association of Engineers

2021

4^{th} Advanced Course on Data Science and Machine Learning (ACDL 2021)

Participation certificate with final exam

July 2021

16^{th} International Computer Vision Summer School (ICVSS 2022)

Participation certificate with final exam

July 2022

ELLIS Summer School on Large-Scale AI for Research and Industry

Participation certificate with final project (NeRF-based camera optimization)

Sept. 2023

Additional information

Citizenship

Italian, German

Travelling Passport, B license, own car

Speaker at conferences _____

 35^{th} IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems

Kyoto, Japan

 21^{st} International Conference on Image Analysis and Processing

Lecce, Italy

 9^{th} International Conference on 3D Vision

Virtual, Online

16th VISIGRAPP

Virtual, Online

 25^{th} International Conference on Pattern Recognition

Virtual, Online

Journals and conferences activities _____

 $2^{nd}\,$ T-CAP 2022 Workshop at ICPR2022

Montreal, Canada 21-25 Aug. 2022

Technical Program Committee

Lecce, Italy

 $1^{st}\,$ T-CAP 2021 Workshop at ICIAP2021 **Technical Program Committee**

23-27 Mag. 2022

16th VISIGRAPP

Virtual, Online

8-10 Feb. 2021

Session chair

Reviewing activities _

IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)

IEEE International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR)

IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)

Towards a Complete Analysis of People: From Face and Body to Clothes (T-CAP)

International Workshop and Challenge on People Analysis (WCPA)

Teaching activities __

School in AI: Deep Learning, Vision and Language for Industry - first edition

Modena, Italy

Laboratory Lecturer - 3D Computer Vision

Feb. 2022

School in AI: Deep Learning, Vision and Language for Industry - second edition

Modena, Italy

Laboratory Lecturer - 3D Computer Vision

Sept. 2022

Thesis supervision _

MSc Thesis (G. Doganieri)

"3D Multi-Person Pose Estimation and Skeleton tracking by a single RGB camera"

Feb. 2022

Publications _____

More info on Google Scholar.

JOURNALS

Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL)

A.D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R.Cucchiara "Depth-based 3D human pose refinement: Evaluating the refinet framework"

Mar. 2023

Computers & Graphics

A. Caputo, A. Giacchetti, S. Soso, D. Pintani, A. D'Eusanio, S. Pini, G. Borghi, A. Simoni, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara, et al.

Oct. 2021

"SHREC 2021: skeleton-based hand gesture recognition in the wild"

Informatics

A. D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "Multimodal hand gesture classification for the human-car interaction"

Aug. 2020

CONFERENCES

aard . .

23^{ra} International Conference on Image Analysis and Processing	Udine, Italy
D. Di Nucci, A. Simoni, M. Tomei, L. Ciuffreda, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "CarPatch: A Synthetic Benchmark for Radiance Field Evaluation on Vehicle Components"	11-15 Sept. 2023
35^{th} International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems + RA-L	Kyoto, Japan
A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani "Semi-Perspective Decoupled Heatmaps for 3D Robot Pose Estimation from Depth Maps"	23-27 Oct. 2022
21^{st} International Conference on Image Analysis And Processing	Lecce, Italy
S. Pini, G. Borghi, A. D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, R. Vezzani "Unsupervised detection of dynamic hand gestures from leap motion data"	23-27 Mag. 2022

"Unsupervised detection of dynamic hand gestures from leap motion data" 9^{th} International Conference on 3D Vision

Virtual, Online

1-3 Dec. 2021

A. Simoni, S. Pini, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "Multi-category mesh reconstruction from image collections"

Virtual, Online

 16^{th} VISIGRAPP A. Simoni, A. D'Eusanio, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani "Improving car model classification through vehicle keypoint localization"

"Extracting accurate long-term behavior changes from a large pig dataset"

8-10 Feb. 2021 Virtual, Online

 16^{th} **VISIGRAPP** L. Bergamini, S. Pini, A. Simoni, R. Vezzani, S. Calderara, R. B. D'Eath, R. B. Fisher

8-10 Feb. 2021

$25^{th}\,$ International Conference on Pattern Recognition

A. Simoni, L. Bergamini, A. Palazzi, S. Calderara, R. Cucchiara "Future urban scene generation through vehicle synthesis"

Virtual, Online 10-15 Jan. 2021

$8^{th}\,$ International Conference on 3D Vision

A. D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "A transformer-based network for dynamic hand gesture recognition"

Virtual, Online 25-28 Nov. 2020

3

According to law 679/2016 of the Regulation of the European Parliament of 27th April 2016, I hereby express my consent to process and use my data provided in this document and application for recruiting purposes.

October 8, 2023 Alessandro Simoni - resume